Now that we've
covered the importance
of internal
authentication and what
might happen if we
don't enable it,
we're going to cover
how to implement it.
So let's look at an
example of a replica set.
Currently, the members
of this replica set
don't have to
authenticate to each other
when joining the replica
set or replicating data
from the primary.
This is dangerous, because if
a bad actor gains admin access
to the primary, they could
potentially add their own rogue
member to the replica set.
So to mitigate this,
we're going to implement
SCRAM internal authentication.
We've actually already looked
at SCRAM authentication
in chapter 1 when we discuss
usernames and passwords
as credentials for
authentication.
However, when SCRAM is used
for internal authentication,
it accepts keyfiles as
credentials instead.
A keyfile is a file with
a very long password.
The keyfile is copied over to
each member of the replica set
and it must be presented
to other members
during authentication.
So now that we've seen
a diagram of SCRAM
internal authentication,
let's move to the command line
and start implementing it.
All right, so to
begin, I'm going
to identify the keyfiles
that each member will
use to authenticate.
So here's the keyfile
for the first member,
here's the keyfile
for the second member,
and here's the keyfile
for the third member.
So all these keyfiles
have the same contents,
but I just want to note that
we have three copies of it.
All right, so now that we know
that our keyfiles are in place,
we can modify the configuration
files to include links
to these keyfiles.
I'm going to open this first
configuration file using vi,
but if you're doing
this in the IDE later,
you can use the file editor
instead of opening this file
from the command line.
So I'm going to edit the
first member's configuration
to use the keyfile.
And as a note, the keyfile
configuration option implicitly
turns on authentication for
replica set members and MongoDB
users.
So instead of writing
"authorization enabled"
in addition to the
keyfile option,
we can just write
"keyfile" to enforce
both types of authentication.
So now I'm going to edit the
second member's configuration.
And now I'll update the
third member's configuration.
OK, so at this stage, all
three configuration files
have been modified
to use keyfiles
for internal authentication.
Now we just need to start
each replica set member
with the new configuration.
So here's the first
one, it looks OK.
Here's the second
And the third one,
yep, looks OK.
So now that all the
members are up and running,
I'm going to initiate
the replica set.
So first, I'll connect to one of
the members of the replica set,
and I will run rs.initiate
to initiate the replica set.
So it looks like the
set has been initiated,
so after a few seconds it
should tell me that I'm
connected to the primary node.
So now, because we connected
to this member over localhost,
I can create the first user
using the localhost exception.
So I'm going to switch
to the admin database,
and I'll create our
user administrator
on the admin database.
And it looks like
it was successful.
So that's our first user.
Let's just authenticate
as that user now.
And it was successful.
So at this point, the user
administrator can do their job
and create other users.
So, we're done.
So let's recap what we learned.
To implement internal
authentication
in a three-member replica
set using keyfiles,
you must have three
copies of the keyfile,
with one available
to each member,
modify all three configuration
files to link each keyfile,
and then restart MongoDB
with the new configuration,
and lastly, create
the first user using
the localhost exception.